# Nicklas Hansen

Github: nicklashansen | LinkedIn: ncklas

[ (+45) 61 26 46 82 | ≥ hello@nicklashansen.com | ½ nicklashansen.com | ⊌ 23 | ↑ Berkeley, CA

## Research interest

I am highly interested in research on the generalization and robustness of deep learning systems, particularly in connection with self-supervision, transfer learning and optimization. I work with reinforcement learning, computer vision, audio, and biomedicine. I strive to make artificial intelligence available to a broader audience through research and open source projects.

## **Education**

#### **University of California, Berkeley**

Berkeley, CA

Visiting Student & Research Intern at Berkeley Artificial Intelligence Research Lab

Spring 2020

A semester devoted to deep learning research at BAIR, supplemented by a class on data-driven innovation.

Participant in Innovation Centre Denmark's SPARK program and recipient of the Spar Nord Foundation Scholarship.

# **Technical University of Denmark**

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

M.Sc. Mathematical Modelling & Computing GPA: 10.7 (-3 to 12)

Feb 2019 -

Largely focused on special topics in deep learning such as deep reinforcement learning, deep unsupervised learning, optimization for deep learning and research on novel applications of deep learning.

#### **Technical University of Denmark**

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

B.Sc. Software Engineering GPA: 8.2 (-3 to 12)

Sep 2015 - Dec 2018

Built a strong foundation in machine learning, linear algebra, statistics, calculus, algorithms and digital signal processing.

#### **Nanyang Technological University**

Singapore

**Exchange Student** 

Fall 2017

Courses in computer vision, cryptology and large-scale software engineering.

# **Professional experience**

#### **Technical University of Denmark**

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

**Teaching Assistant** 

Fall 2019

02456 Deep Learning & 02454 Introduction to Cognitive Science

I taught 6 hours a week, developed course material, corrected assignments and supervised 50+ students' projects on the topics of deep reinforcement learning and self-supervised learning for audio.

**Retune DSP** 

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

**Assistant Software Developer** 

Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

I helped a team of engineers build and maintain deep learning pipelines for embedded voice control systems.

Raffle.ai

Copenhagen, Denmark

Machine Learning Intern

Summer 2019

I reimplemented the SyntaxSQLNet cross-domain text-to-SQL parser in PyTorch and improved its accuracy by 12%. https://github.com/raffle-interns/SyntaxSQLNet

**Nordic Transition** 

Gentofte, Denmark

Lead Software Developer

Jul 2017 - Dec 2019

I developed and maintained a GDPR-compliant data management and analysis platform for the HR industry.

## Summer schools

Åbo Akademi

Development of high-assured autonomous systems

Turku, Finland Aug 2018

**Tallinn Technical University** 

High-assured autonomous systems

Tallinn, Estonia Jun 2018

## Certificates

**Dansk Standard** 

ISO21500 Guidance on Project Management

Copenhagen, Denmark Jan 2018

# **Current projects**

Short Term Blood Glucose Prediction Based on Continuous Glucose Monitoring Data

Under review

Under review for IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (Jan 2020)

Pre-print available for download here: <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.02805">https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.02805</a>

A. Mohebbi, A. Johansen, N. Hansen, P. Christensen, J. Tarp, M. Jensen, H. Bengtsson, M. Mørup

# Open source contributions

Optimization in deep learning

Dec 2019

Collection of recent deep learning optimization algorithms (50+ stars)

https://github.com/nicklashansen/neural-net-optimization

How to build RNNs and LSTMs from scratch with NumPy

Oct 2019

Educational material on recurrent neural networks (100+ stars)

https://github.com/nicklashansen/rnn\_lstm\_from\_scratch

**Minimal Neural Architecture Search** 

Oct 2019

A minimalistic NAS implementation for educational purposes (30+ stars)

https://github.com/nicklashansen/minimal-nas

**Voice Activity Detection in Noisy Environments** 

Dec 2018

Study on VAD systems robust to high noise levels (20+ stars) https://github.com/nicklashansen/voice-activity-detection

#### Academic reviews

# ACL, Annual Conference of the Association for Computational Linguistics

2020

Assisted review

## **Volunteer work**

# Atlas, a battleground for the Starcraft II World Championships

Used in GSL, GSTL, IPL, DreamHack, Assembly and more (200k+ spectators)

Dec 2012 - Nov 2013

# **Technical skills**

Programming

Python, C#, C++, C, Java, JavaScript, Matlab, SQL

**Deep Learning** PyTorch, TensorFlow

Others Linux, Git, Azure, AWS, Docker, Conda, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, Latex